

Qin Yu (Eric)

+86 18584515196 qinyu8331@163.com

Male (1988/09/10) Living in Shanghai

Recent Work

Highest Degree

Major:

Position: AVP Data & MI, CCS, WPB COO Office

Company: HSBC China

Industry: Banking

School: Royal Holloway, University of London

Accounting

Degree: Master of Science

Basic Info.

Address: Shanghai Age: 32

Height: 181cm Marital Status: Unmarried

Self-evaluation

Certified SAS programmer & skilled Python programmer, with 6 years of experience in retail banking data managing, reporting & analytics, covering various aspects of retail banking business including wealth management, credit card, and personal loans. Have good command of SAS, SQL, Python languages, and solid understanding of data warehouse management, including developing codes, testing for quality assurance, and monitoring of performance.

Work Experience

2018/9-Present HSBC China / CCS Operational Analytics, WPB COO Office / AVP (Data & MI)

- 1. Develop collection segmentation model with logistic regression & decision tree on past due & M1 delinquent card customers to identify clients with greater propensity to repay debts. Design differentiated collection strategies for different groups of customers accordingly, by assessing repayment profile of each type of client proposed by the model.
- Develop skip predictive model with gradient boosting machine learning (GBDT), to identify clients most li
 kely to skip and take early actions. Enabled collection team to better handle high-propensity skip custom
 ers with accelerated process & enhanced opportunities for RMT offerings.
- 3. Develop credit card management information framework (MI) and present 20+ reports on a monthly basi s in support of underwriting & collection operation, enabling card full life cycle analysis covering acquisiti on, activation, utilization, and collection stages. Keep close track of key indicators such as approval rate, TAT (turn around time), coincident/ lag delinquency rate, flow rate, etc.

2017/9-2018/9 Citibank China / Retail Banking Decision Management / Assistant Manager

1. Build decision tree model on over 450K customers to target high-propensity audience for key RB products (including Insurance, QDII, certificate deposit, etc.), fueling up over 2 million insurance & MF cross sales mon thly from credit card customer base to retail banking.

- 2. Re-build logistic model to predict deposit outflow & customer attrition, enabling smooth branch optimization , customer re-allocation with minimized negative impacts.
- 3. Build customer tagging system containing over 2,000 tags covering 16 dimensions, to achieve hyper-perso nalized marketing and customer profiling, help business to reach clients with highly differentiated services.
- 4. Perform statistical analysis on business performance & operation, identifying key issues and design solutions accordingly.
- 5. Produce monthly incentive reports involving 100+ wealth management & insurance sales employees, keep track of sales performance metrics, optimize incentive plan to achieve better results.

2014/9-2017/8

Ping An Bank / Retail Banking Management / Deputy Manager / Data Analysis

- 1. Develop and present weekly and monthly business reports, with a focus on KPI targeting and trending ana lysis, to retail banking leadership.
- 2. Perform analyses on business performance monthly, help leadership make key strategic decision on products and services.
- 3. Produce monthly incentive reports involving 150+ front-line employees, and conduct analysis of sales performance metrics, re-design incentive plans to boost better performance.
- 4. Leverage data mining techniques to form vivid customer profile & better customer segmentation.

Education

2013/9-2014/9 Royal Holloway, University of London

Msc in International Accounting

Degree with **Distinction**, top 5% in students

2009/9-2013/9 Sichuan International Studies University

Bachelor in English

Multiple time first-tier scholarship winner, top 5% in students

Certifications

SAS Base Certified Programmer (Global)

2018/3

2016/3	PAT Programming Certificate (awarded by Zhejiang University)
2013/3	TEM Level 8 (Test for English Majors, awarded by China Ministry of Education)